<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
<title>The Practical Utopian</title>
<description>The latest content from the Practopian</description>
<link>http://www.Practopian.org</link>
<atom:link href="http://www.Practopian.org/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<language>en-us</language>
<managingEditor>hbowie@Practopian.org (Herb Bowie)</managingEditor>
<webMaster>hbowie@Practopian.org (Herb Bowie)</webMaster>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 00:00 PDT</lastBuildDate>
<pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 00:00 PDT</pubDate>
<ttl>1440</ttl>
<item>
<title>Blog Post: The System is Working Very Well, Thank You</title>
<link>http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/the-system-is-working-very-well-thank-you.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/the-system-is-working-very-well-thank-you.html</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 00:00 PDT</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;We need to realize that the current system is, in fact, not broken. Instead, in truth, it is doing exactly what it was designed to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Blog Post: Rejiggering Our Religion</title>
<link>http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/rejiggering-our-religion.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/rejiggering-our-religion.html</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 00:00 PDT</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to religion, the main question for most people is whether to keep the one we were raised with or to lose it altogether. But now I’m starting to wonder whether, instead of losing my religion, it might not be better just to rejigger it a bit?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Blog Post: Apollo 11 - The Most Important Movie You&apos;ll See This Year</title>
<link>http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/apollo-11-the-most-important-movie-youll-see-this-year.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/apollo-11-the-most-important-movie-youll-see-this-year.html</guid>
<pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 00:00 PDT</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;No matter what your age or orientation, it’s hard to gainsay the significance of humankind’s first trip through space to set foot on a celestial body other than our birth planet. Of course fictional space flight has become so common that sitting down for two hours to watch a documentary about a real trip that took place half a century ago might seem like a somewhat pedestrian enterprise. Ah, but there’s where you’d be wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Blog Post: What the Latest Trump Attack Means for Democrats</title>
<link>http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/what-the-latest-trump-attack-means-for-democrats.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/what-the-latest-trump-attack-means-for-democrats.html</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 00:00 PDT</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;By now I’m sure you’ve heard of Trump’s recent attacks on four Democratic congressional representatives, all women of color, urging them to “go back … to the crime-infested places from which they came.” How should Democrats respond? Here are the sorts of positions I’d like to hear them articulate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Blog Post: The Dangers of Political Nostalgia</title>
<link>http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/the-dangers-of-political-nostalgia.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/the-dangers-of-political-nostalgia.html</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00 PDT</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;I’m not quite as old as Biden, and I’ve never served in public office, but I can still share his nostalgia for seemingly simpler times when our political leaders displayed some sort of respect for each other, even when they disagreed over issues of state. However it’s one thing to reveal a preference for certain elements of those bygone days, but quite another to base your presidential run on wishful thinking that those lost elements can somehow be restored in the third decade of the 21st century.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Blog Post: The Progressive Problem</title>
<link>http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/the-progressive-problem.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/the-progressive-problem.html</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 00:00 PDT</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;No wonder zombie movies have been popular of late: so many of us feel like increasingly isolated survivors having to fight off forces that we thought were previously vanquished and long buried, forces that seem to be arising all around us, springing at us from all sides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Blog Post: How to Fix Big Tech</title>
<link>http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/how-to-fix-big-tech.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/how-to-fix-big-tech.html</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 00:00 PDT</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;We all sort of know the problems, right? Monopolies. Lock-in. Stream addiction. Reality bubbles. Billionaires seeking market dominance. All other values taking a back seat to growth. I don’t think I need to elaborate. If you’re reading this, then you’re probably well aware of all these concerns. But what do we do about them? Here are a couple of ideas. Radical but practical. And very doable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Appreciation: Building a Case for the Detective Story</title>
<link>http://www.Practopian.org/appreciation/building-a-case-for-the-detective-story.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.Practopian.org/appreciation/building-a-case-for-the-detective-story.html</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00 PDT</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;Over the many years since the receipt of my Bachelor’s degree in English from the University of Michigan, I have probably spent more rewarding hours reading detective stories than any other form of fiction. Such reliance on a particular genre is often viewed as a marked deficiency in taste and erudition, so I’d like to take a few minutes to defend my predilection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Blog Post: The Challenge for Democrats: Playing the Long Game</title>
<link>http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/the-challenge-for-democrats-playing-the-long-game.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/the-challenge-for-democrats-playing-the-long-game.html</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 00:00 PDT</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;Right now Democrats are focused primarily on two things happening in 2020: 1. Beating Trump; 2. Regaining control of the Senate. These would both be great accomplishments for the party, and for the winning candidates. But for the country, not so much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Blog Post: The Devastating Tragedy of our Vanishing Middle Class</title>
<link>http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/the-devastating-tragedy-of-our-vanishing-middle-class.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/the-devastating-tragedy-of-our-vanishing-middle-class.html</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 00:00 PDT</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;If you react in any of these typical ways, then I will argue today that you’re missing the bigger picture, and overlooking the most devastating consequences of our country’s loss of our middle class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Appreciation: Paul Thorn and his 800 Pound Jesus</title>
<link>http://www.Practopian.org/appreciation/paul-thorn-and-his-800-pound-jesus.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.Practopian.org/appreciation/paul-thorn-and-his-800-pound-jesus.html</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 00:00 PDT</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;I’d been aware of Paul Thorn for some time, but didn’t really become a fan until I saw him live last summer at The Ark in Ann Arbor. I convinced an old University of Michigan roommate to come with me while I was in town, as an opportunity to catch up, but we were both caught off guard by how much we loved Thorn’s show. I’ve been listening to Thorn’s recordings regularly since then, and can now bear witness to a great catalog that bears deep and repeated listening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Blog Post: How a Balanced Candidate Might Win the Presidency</title>
<link>http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/how-a-balanced-candidate-might-win-the-presidency.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/how-a-balanced-candidate-might-win-the-presidency.html</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 00:00 PDT</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;I wrote recently to express my skepticism about the chances of a  centrist candidate becoming our next U.S. president. I write today to share my belief that a balanced candidate might well win.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Blog Post: My List of Requirements for our Next President</title>
<link>http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/my-list-of-requirements-for-our-next-president.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/my-list-of-requirements-for-our-next-president.html</guid>
<pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2019 00:00 PDT</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;While many of us are waiting for our 2020 presidential candidates to hit the road and give us a chance to to get to know them better, I decided to stop waiting and let them know what I’m looking for in a new president. I mean after all, it doesn’t seem fair to make them guess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Blog Post: Citizen Kane vs. Citizen Bailey</title>
<link>http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/citizen-kane-vs-citizen-bailey.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/citizen-kane-vs-citizen-bailey.html</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 00:00 PDT</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;I’ve often considered &lt;em&gt;Citizen Kane&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;It’s A Wonderful Life&lt;/em&gt; to be complementary works, much like cinematic twins separated at birth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Blog Post: Our Three Human Approaches to Dealing with Problems</title>
<link>http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/our-three-human-approaches-to-dealing-with-problems.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/our-three-human-approaches-to-dealing-with-problems.html</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00 PST</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;We all run into challenges from time to time, whether at work, at home, or in our communities. In general, I would suggest, we have three different approaches available to us when we try to respond to such situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Basic Info: Science</title>
<link>http://www.Practopian.org/basics/science.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.Practopian.org/basics/science.html</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 00:00 PST</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;A belief in science is one of the core Practopian principles. We embrace science as one way of understanding the universe in which we live, and we accept toolmaking (aka engineering) as one means of improving the human condition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Blog Post: Is There Any Middle Left?</title>
<link>http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/is-there-any-middle-left.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/is-there-any-middle-left.html</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 00:00 PST</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;As the US political scene transitions from the Democratic successes in the midterms to the beginnings of the 2020 presidential contest, one of the most pressing questions to emerge is whether there is any meaningful middle ground remaining along the political spectrum stretching from left to right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Blog Post: Rebuilding Trust In Our Large Institutions</title>
<link>http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/rebuilding-trust-in-our-large-institutions.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/rebuilding-trust-in-our-large-institutions.html</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 00:00 PST</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;I find it fascinating to compare the original &lt;em&gt;Star Trek&lt;/em&gt; television series with the first &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; movie. And I think this comparison can reveal a lot about the current state of our culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Blog Post: Our American Class System</title>
<link>http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/our-american-class-system.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/our-american-class-system.html</guid>
<pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 00:00 PST</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;In short, this was a period of our history during which class distinctions seemed to be fading. Sure, some people had more money than others. My mother drove a Ford Falcon, my father drove a Mustang, and my Uncle drove a Thunderbird. But they all drove Fords, everyone drove cars built in Detroit, and the similarities between the cars they were driving were more significant than the differences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Basic Info: More Love</title>
<link>http://www.Practopian.org/basics/more-love.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.Practopian.org/basics/more-love.html</guid>
<pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 00:00 PST</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;For me, love is an elemental human feeling that helps to bind us to one another, and to the world around us. It is a feeling of care and appreciation for, and attachment to, people and things of value that have an independent existence outside of ourselves. And while love may not be “&lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; we need,” it does seem to be an essential starting point for everything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
