<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
<title>The Practical Utopian</title>
<description>The latest content from the Practopian</description>
<link>http://www.Practopian.org</link>
<atom:link href="http://www.Practopian.org/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<language>en-us</language>
<managingEditor>hbowie@Practopian.org (Herb Bowie)</managingEditor>
<webMaster>hbowie@Practopian.org (Herb Bowie)</webMaster>
<lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00 PDT</lastBuildDate>
<pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00 PDT</pubDate>
<ttl>1440</ttl>
<item>
<title>Blog Post: Patterns of Human Cooperation</title>
<link>http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/patterns-of-human-cooperation.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/patterns-of-human-cooperation.html</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 00:00 PDT</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;As humans our superpower is the ability to work cooperatively with others of our species. But these seemingly simple ideas of cooperation and coordination turn out to be devilishly complex in practice, especially in large undertakings. In an organization of any appreciable size, all of the following patterns of cooperation can be found. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Blog Post: Understanding Human History</title>
<link>http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/understanding-human-history.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/understanding-human-history.html</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 00:00 PDT</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;When I was in school, history was one of my least favorite subjects: It just seemed like a bunch of arbitrary names and dates and events that I had to memorize. In hindsight, I realize now, the problem I had with the subject was that it had been &amp;#8220;storified.&amp;#8221; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Blog Post: Why I Use Markdown (And Why You Should Too)</title>
<link>http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/why-i-use-markdown-and-why-you-should-too.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/why-i-use-markdown-and-why-you-should-too.html</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 00:00 PST</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;What is Markdown, and why should you care? Let&apos;s just start by saying that Markdown is a deceptively simple tool for writers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Blog Post: What Trump Gets Right</title>
<link>http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/what-trump-gets-right.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/what-trump-gets-right.html</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 00:00 PST</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;As we move into the 2020 election season in the US, I thought it might be useful to point out some things that Donald Trump gets right. If you&apos;re concerned about electability, then please pay attention to how your candidates navigate their ways through these seven minefields. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Blog Post: Assessment of Democratic Presidential Candidates - Jan 2020</title>
<link>http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/assessment-of-democratic-presidential-candidates-jan-2020.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/assessment-of-democratic-presidential-candidates-jan-2020.html</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 00:00 PST</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;This is my assessment of the Democratic candidates for the US presidency, following the debates on the evening of 14 Jan 2020. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Blog Post: Dethroning the False God of User Experience Design</title>
<link>http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/dethroning-the-false-god-of-user-experience-design.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/dethroning-the-false-god-of-user-experience-design.html</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 00:00 PST</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;The problem is that we&apos;ve had something valuable stolen from us along the way. And the whole modern notion of UX design is one of the thieves that has robbed us. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Blog Post: My Prayer for a More Integral New Year</title>
<link>http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/my-prayer-for-a-more-integral-new-year.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/my-prayer-for-a-more-integral-new-year.html</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 00:00 PST</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;As 2019 winds to a close, and we pause briefly to compose ourselves before finding out what 2020 has in store, I want to take a moment to offer up a prayer &amp;#8211; not to God, but to all of us &amp;#8211; for a more integral sense of who we are in the new year. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Blog Post: The Personal vs. The Institutional</title>
<link>http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/the-personal-vs-the-institutional.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/the-personal-vs-the-institutional.html</guid>
<pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00 PDT</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;The problem here is that this conflict between the personal and the institutional is a false dichotomy. While we are right to believe that the ultimate goal of human society is the welfare of the individual persons within that society, it is folly to believe that these ends can be met without participation in and reliance on human institutions. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Blog Post: The System is Working Very Well, Thank You</title>
<link>http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/the-system-is-working-very-well-thank-you.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/the-system-is-working-very-well-thank-you.html</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 00:00 PDT</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;We need to realize that the current system is, in fact, not broken. Instead, in truth, it is doing exactly what it was designed to do. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Blog Post: Rejiggering Our Religion</title>
<link>http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/rejiggering-our-religion.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/rejiggering-our-religion.html</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 00:00 PDT</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to religion, the main question for most people is whether to keep the one we were raised with or to lose it altogether. But now I&apos;m starting to wonder whether, instead of losing my religion, it might not be better just to rejigger it a bit? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Blog Post: Apollo 11 - The Most Important Movie You&apos;ll See This Year</title>
<link>http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/apollo-11-the-most-important-movie-youll-see-this-year.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/apollo-11-the-most-important-movie-youll-see-this-year.html</guid>
<pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 00:00 PDT</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;No matter what your age or orientation, it&apos;s hard to gainsay the significance of humankind&apos;s first trip through space to set foot on a celestial body other than our birth planet. Of course fictional space flight has become so common that sitting down for two hours to watch a documentary about a real trip that took place half a century ago might seem like a somewhat pedestrian enterprise. Ah, but there&apos;s where you&apos;d be wrong. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Blog Post: What the Latest Trump Attack Means for Democrats</title>
<link>http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/what-the-latest-trump-attack-means-for-democrats.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/what-the-latest-trump-attack-means-for-democrats.html</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 00:00 PDT</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;By now I&apos;m sure you&apos;ve heard of Trump&apos;s recent attacks on four Democratic congressional representatives, all women of color, urging them to &amp;#8220;go back &amp;#8230; to the crime-infested places from which they came.&amp;#8221; How should Democrats respond? Here are the sorts of positions I&apos;d like to hear them articulate. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Blog Post: The Dangers of Political Nostalgia</title>
<link>http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/the-dangers-of-political-nostalgia.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/the-dangers-of-political-nostalgia.html</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00 PDT</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m not quite as old as Biden, and I&apos;ve never served in public office, but I can still share his nostalgia for seemingly simpler times when our political leaders displayed some sort of respect for each other, even when they disagreed over issues of state. However it&apos;s one thing to reveal a preference for certain elements of those bygone days, but quite another to base your presidential run on wishful thinking that those lost elements can somehow be restored in the third decade of the 21st century. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Blog Post: The Progressive Problem</title>
<link>http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/the-progressive-problem.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/the-progressive-problem.html</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 00:00 PDT</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;No wonder zombie movies have been popular of late: so many of us feel like increasingly isolated survivors having to fight off forces that we thought were previously vanquished and long buried, forces that seem to be arising all around us, springing at us from all sides. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Blog Post: How to Fix Big Tech</title>
<link>http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/how-to-fix-big-tech.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/how-to-fix-big-tech.html</guid>
<pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2019 00:00 PDT</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;We all sort of know the problems, right? Monopolies. Lock-in. Stream addiction. Reality bubbles. Billionaires seeking market dominance. All other values taking a back seat to growth. I don&apos;t think I need to elaborate. If you&apos;re reading this, then you&apos;re probably well aware of all these concerns. But what do we do about them? Here are a couple of ideas. Radical but practical. And very doable. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Appreciation: Building a Case for the Detective Story</title>
<link>http://www.Practopian.org/appreciation/building-a-case-for-the-detective-story.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.Practopian.org/appreciation/building-a-case-for-the-detective-story.html</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00 PDT</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;Over the many years since the receipt of my Bachelor&apos;s degree in English from the University of Michigan, I have probably spent more rewarding hours reading detective stories than any other form of fiction. Such reliance on a particular genre is often viewed as a marked deficiency in taste and erudition, so I&apos;d like to take a few minutes to defend my predilection. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Blog Post: The Challenge for Democrats: Playing the Long Game</title>
<link>http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/the-challenge-for-democrats-playing-the-long-game.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/the-challenge-for-democrats-playing-the-long-game.html</guid>
<pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 00:00 PDT</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;Right now Democrats are focused primarily on two things happening in 2020: 1. Beating Trump; 2. Regaining control of the Senate. These would both be great accomplishments for the party, and for the winning candidates. But for the country, not so much. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Blog Post: The Devastating Tragedy of our Vanishing Middle Class</title>
<link>http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/the-devastating-tragedy-of-our-vanishing-middle-class.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/the-devastating-tragedy-of-our-vanishing-middle-class.html</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 00:00 PDT</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;If you react in any of these typical ways, then I will argue today that you&apos;re missing the bigger picture, and overlooking the most devastating consequences of our country&apos;s loss of our middle class. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Appreciation: Paul Thorn and his 800 Pound Jesus</title>
<link>http://www.Practopian.org/appreciation/paul-thorn-and-his-800-pound-jesus.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.Practopian.org/appreciation/paul-thorn-and-his-800-pound-jesus.html</guid>
<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 00:00 PDT</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;I&apos;d been aware of Paul Thorn for some time, but didn&apos;t really become a fan until I saw him live last summer at The Ark in Ann Arbor. I convinced an old University of Michigan roommate to come with me while I was in town, as an opportunity to catch up, but we were both caught off guard by how much we loved Thorn&apos;s show. I&apos;ve been listening to Thorn&apos;s recordings regularly since then, and can now bear witness to a great catalog that bears deep and repeated listening. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
<item>
<title>Blog Post: How a Balanced Candidate Might Win the Presidency</title>
<link>http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/how-a-balanced-candidate-might-win-the-presidency.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.Practopian.org/blog/hbowie/how-a-balanced-candidate-might-win-the-presidency.html</guid>
<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 00:00 PDT</pubDate>
<description>
&lt;p&gt;I wrote recently to express my skepticism about the chances of a  centrist candidate becoming our next U.S. president. I write today to share my belief that a balanced candidate might well win. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Author: Herb Bowie &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
